以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好吧，我只想说下一个话题
okay let me just say our next topic
真正走向机器学习
moving really toward machine learning
将是该部分的最后一部分
would be the last section of section of
第六章关于随机梯度
chapter six about stochastic gradient
下降我认为教授sois来自
descent I think professor sois from
计算机科学就是他能够做到的
computer science is if he's able he will
星期五上课并告诉我们
take the class Friday and tell us about
性病随机梯度下降
STDs stochastic gradient descent
关键算法我的意思是在a
critical algorithm I mean that at a
快速浏览
quick look
随机梯度下降就是这样
stochastic gradient descent is does
一次较小的批次，所以它
smaller batches at a time so it's
计算速度比纯粹快
computationally faster than pure
梯度下降但也随机
gradient descent but also stochastic
梯度下降是能够解决的
gradient descent is able to solve
你所处的概率问题
probabilistic problems where you're
试图最小化预期值
trying to minimize an expected value
而不是功能，无论如何它是一个
instead of a function anyway it's a
重要的是实际上有一个
important thing actually there's a
讲座下午两点在大脑中
lecture at two o'clock in brain in
关于梯度下降的神经科学
neuroscience about the gradient descent
算法然后是博伊德教授
algorithms and then professor Boyd is
今天下午4:30在这里发言
speaking here at 4:30 this afternoon
它是压倒性的，所以我要去
it's overwhelming so so I'm going to
今天谈谈几个主题
talk today about several topics that are
优化线性的特定部分
specific parts of optimization linear
编程是一个非常着名的部分
programming is a very famous part of
优化我不知道你是否见过面
optimization I don't know if you've met
我觉得值得知道的是什么
it I think it's worth knowing that what
输入是什么，关键事实是什么
the inputs are and what's the key fact
关于线性编程，当然
about linear programming and of course
还有什么算法
also what are the algorithms that's
通常我们想知道的是什么
usually what we want to know what's the
问题是什么的结果
problem what are the results the
数学结果又是什么
mathematical results and what are the
计算工具是的，所以这是一个
computational tools yeah so that's a
非常确定的最大流量最小切割是
very established max-flow min-cut is
一旦
once
特别是线性编程我
specifically linear programming that I
想想也许会成为最好的
think maybe would serve as the best
例子然后是双人游戏
example and then two-person games
你见过那些人吗？你知道吗？
have you met those do so would you know
两个人的规则是什么
what what the rules are at a two-person
零和游戏那些是游戏中的游戏
zero-sum game those are the in game
理论那些是明确的
theory those are the ones that are clear
那里的一切都很好
everything's well established there and
实际上它们相当于或线性
in fact they're equivalent to or linear
程序，这就是为什么这两个是
programs so that's why those two are
进入今天然后是关键事实
coming in today and then the key fact
关于两人游戏和关于线性
about two-person games and about linear
编程是二元的，所以如果有的话
programming is duality so if there's any
在那个板上的字是它的一个
word on that board it's the one in
具有大量内容的大写字母
capital letters that has mass content
好吧，我只是从线性开始
okay I'm just going to start with linear
程序，然后继续前进好吧，那是什么
program and then move on okay so what's
它是一个线性编程线性程序
a linear programming linear program it's
我们正在优化线性成本函数
we're optimizing a linear cost function
所以我们花一分钟来降低成本C.
so we're a minute minimizing the cost C
转置X使得向量X是
transpose X so that vector X is the
不知道我们正在寻找和这个
unknown that we're looking for and this
矢量C是成本载体中，从而是
vector C is the cost vector so that is
c1x1加上CNxn所以你可以看到原因
c1 x1 plus plus CN xn so you can see why
它被称为线性编程
it's called linear programming
成本是约束的线性
the cost is linear the constraints are
也是线性的，所以对X的约束是
also linear so the constraints on X are
我当然是一套线性方程组
set of linear equations of course I'm
没想到是一个正方形
not thinking of a as being a square
可逆矩阵如果是那样就没办法了
invertible matrix no way if it were that
会告诉我们X必须是什么，我们
would tell us what X had to be and we
我们的问题将在于我们拥有的问题
our problem would be over we we have we
有n个未知数，当然这是M？
have n unknowns this is M by n of course
X是n乘1，这是我们未知的向量
X is n by 1 that's our unknown vector
而且我在想M会更小
and I'm thinking that M will be smaller
比n，但我们确实有约束和
than n but we do have constraints and
现在变成了线性的东西
now comes the thing that makes linear
编程不是没有真正的线性和
programming not not actually linear and
这是约束X更大的等于
that's the constraint X greater equal
零，我把它写成矢量
zero and I've written that as a vector
但这意味着x1更大
but that means that means x1 greater
到X等于零所以这是一个向量
equals zero on to X so it's a vector
不平等好，所以我们有一个最小化a
inequality ok so we have a minimizing a
很漂亮的功能
very simple function with pretty
简单的约束，但在
straightforward constraints but in
平等约束所以有
equality constraints so there the
而不是这些是这两个在一起
instead of these are these two together
是和它的约束
are the constraints that and it's in
线性规划中的线性代数
linear algebra in linear programming
语言这称为可行集
language this is called the feasible set
X这是约束集资本没问题
X it's the constraint set capital okay
在笔记中没错，所以让我画画
and in the notes right ok so let me draw
也许可以在这里展示一张图片
a picture to to show maybe here maybe
我只想问你们有多少人
I'll just ask how many of you are
已经熟悉线性编程
already familiar with linear programming
哦真主好吧所以我不会说明这一点
oh Allah okay so I won't labor the point
但是，让我画一张照片，这样我的
but let me just draw a picture so my
图片就在这里，这就是n
picture will be just here so that's n
等于3所以这是X1X2X3
equals 3 so this is the X 1 X 2 X 3
空格和X大于或等于0表示
space and X greater or equal 0 means
这意味着我在这里
what it means that I'm in this
如果它们是正确的八分之一空间
one-eighth of the space right if they're
非负的井我会说象限
non-negative well I would say Quadrant
但我真的应该说八分之一因为
but I really should say octant because
它是整个3d空间的1/8
it's in there's 1/8 of the full 3d space
所以我在这里，然后也许我有M
so I'm in here and then maybe I have M
是
is
也许只是一个约束，所以让
maybe just one constraint like so so let
我把费用说成X1加2X.
me take the cost to be say X 1 plus 2 X
2加5X3说和约束我
2 plus 5 X 3 say and the constraint I'm
只要有一个等式X1加X.
just gonna have one equation X 1 plus X
2让我轻松搞定
2 let me make it easy make that
约束也是一个容易的，所以这是
constraint an easy one too so this is
这就是我们要尽量减少的
the this is what we're going to minimize
这就是我们必须满足的
and that's what we have to satisfy as
以及x等于0，这是一个普通的1
well as x equals 0 so that's a plain 1
等式给出了r3中的一个平面
equation gives us a plane in r3 the
飞机会经历什么打击
plane would go through what hits the
轴在300等的最小的
axes at 3 0 0 and so the minimum the
点必须躺在那架飞机上
point has to lie on that plane and it
必须躺在八分圆，以便飞机
has to lie in the octant so that plane
被切成三角形是的
is chopped off to be a triangle yeah
这是线性的良好可视化
this is a good visualization of linear
编程和结论是什么
programming and what's the conclusion
我们的成本是线性的，结果是
well our cost is linear so the result is
这三个角落中的一个是
that one of these three corners is the
赢家可能会发生它可能发生
winner it could happen it could happen
也许我对这些有相同的价值
that maybe I have equal values on those
两个角落，因此一路走来
two corners and therefore all the way
也将是赢家但是当我
along would be also winners but when I
有一个线性函数它是最大值
have a linear function it's a maximum at
结束，这些是结束那些
the end and these are the ends those
三个角所以三零零零
three corners so so three zero zero zero
三零或零零三是
three zero or zero zero three are the
三个角落
three corners
其中一个是赢家和
and one of those is the winner and the
问题实际上已经解决了
problem is solved and forth in fact for
这种情况，因为我猜是最小化
this case since I'm minimizing I guess
这将是角落
it would be that corner that
风，所以让我给它一个明星而不是xy
wind so let me give it a star not an x-y
s-300因为哦，没有那三个所以
s-300 cuz that oh no that three so the
值竟然是三处
value turned out to be three at the
第3点将它归零，这是明星还可以
point 3 zeros it and that's a star okay
好的好的好的还好什么更多
good good good good okay what what more
我想做什么我说是的应该是的
do I want to do I said yes should it be
所以没有零零零三
so no zero zero zero three
哪来的未来三年由三个这是
where's the next three is three that's
罚款给了我们一个机会，我觉得
fine that gives us a chance I think that
会给我这15分的费用
would give me cost of 15 this would give
我的成本是6，这会给我
me a cost of 6 and that would give me
街对面
across the street
是的，如果我们能做到的话
yeah it's obviously if we could
列举我们所有的角落
enumerate all the corners we would have
获得答案的超快速方式
a super fast way to get the answer but
麻烦当然是大的
the trouble is of course that for large
值和M和n的数量
values and an amount of M and n there
是指数多的角落和我们
are exponentially many corners and we
我不想一直看到它们
don't want to see them all so that's
什么使线性编程需要时间
what makes linear programming take time
对于那里的算法需要创意
and need ideas so for algorithms there
两种类型的算法有两种类型
are two types of algorithms two types of
编码所有这些也是旧的
codes it's all these the older as well
建立的有这样一个方法是
established ones are so one way is the
找到角落的单纯形法
simplex method which finds a corner we
知道最优的是其中一个
know the optimum is some one of the
角落所以它可以找到它会找到一个
corners so it can find it'll find one
角落，我们将去下一个角落
corner and we'll go to the next corner
所以，如果它开始，如果它开始于其中一个
so if it starts if it starts at one of
它会沿着这些角落行进
these corners it will travel along along
降低成本的优势
an edge that lowers the cost and it has
最后停止，因为它是线性的
to stop at the end because it's linear
成本将继续下降和下降
the cost will keep going down and going
直到它陷入颠簸
down until it bumps up into bumps into
结束点，然后它不能去
the end point and then it can't go
进一步然后我们将从那个下一个
further and then we would from that next
角落我们会去每个角落的下一个角落
corner we would go to a next corner each
时间就像最陡峭的下降
time it's like steepest descent on the
从第一个弯道精读边缘我们
con the edges we from the first corner
我们走得最陡，直到我们不能去
we go the steepest way till we can't go
我们进一步打了另一个角落，我们
further we've hit another corner and we
然后我们重新计算线性代数
and we recompute a linear algebra find
哪个方向最陡峭
which direction is steepest from there
而且这就是。的想法
and and so that's the idea of the
单纯形法由...发明
simplex method which was invented by
跳舞和代数不会去
dancing and and the algebra is not going
在今天的演讲中，但它是
to be in today's lecture but it's
人们必须直截了当
straightforward well people have to
优化它，因为这是一个高度
optimize it because that's a highly
经常使用的方法是的，但是
frequently used method yeah okay but
然后大约20年后或许30年
then about 20 years later maybe or 30 I
记得去市中心的一个讲座
remember going to a lecture in downtown
波士顿由karmarkar所以我必须把他的
Boston by karmarkar so I have to put his
命名我们的标记，他在
name down our marker and he was in the
所有的报纸都是纽约时报
New York Times all the newspapers so it
他有另一种选择是一件大事
was a big deal he had an alternative
算法和他的确切算法
algorithm and the exact algorithm he he
提议直到今天才存活下来但是
proposed hasn't survived until today but
这个想法已经和当时的想法是去
the idea has and the idea was to go to
在可行集内旅行而不是
travel inside the feasible set and not
在边缘
around the edges
所以他的想法因为在这里我们
so his idea because in in in here we
也许在靠近那边开始旅行
maybe travel down near that edge start
再次旅行，所以它最陡峭
again travel again so its steepest
在约束集中的下降
descent in the in the constraint set the
可行集，你可以使用微积分
feasible set and you can use calculus
和这个想法所以这就是这个
and and this idea so this is this is
内点法，所以我只会用
interior point methods so I'll just use
内部这个词告诉我们
the word interior that's telling us that
我们是我们的可行集内，我们
we're we're inside the feasible set we
不打老远来了
don't hit come all the way to the
故意因为我们想要的边界
boundary intentionally because we want
移动和寻找衍生物的空间
room to move and to find derivatives
空的牛顿的消息最小化
empty whose Newton's message to minimize
你看到你选择一个搜索方向
you see you choose a search Direction
正如所有优化所做的那样
just as all of optimization does and in
搜索方向你跟踪它和
that search Direction you track it and
你碰到之前就会停下来
you come you stop before you bump into
然后是可行集的边缘
the edge of the feasible set and then
你可以再次计算衍生物
you compute derivatives again so you can
使用微积分，这是一种方法
use calculus and it it's a method that
这是一个想法，内部的想法来了
it's an idea that the interior idea came
在汽车标记之前，但他超级
before car marker but he got super
宣传，使之真正得到重视了
publicity so it really got attention got
新想法和新想法部分来了
new thinking and new ideas came partly
来自麻省理工学院的人和这两个人
from people at MIT and and these two are
现在仍然没有人参加比赛
now still locked in competition no one
并没有打败对方
hasn't beaten the other in in all
线性编程就是这样的问题
problems so so linear programming is
这里然后进行非线性编程
here but then for nonlinear programming
成本为二次规划
quadratic programming where the cost is
二次非线性规划半
quadratic nonlinear programming semi
明确的编程就是你的所在
definite programming that's where you
有矩阵未知的矩阵
have a matrix unknown a matrix
约束那些更多
constraints those are all the more
复杂的你得到的越多
complicated you get the more it tends to
是
be
内部点方法没关系，这是一个
interior point methods okay that's a
线性编程总结我现在
summary of linear programming now I'd
想举个例子然后我
like to give an example and then I
没有告诉你主要的好让我
haven't told you the main well let me
告诉你关于二元性的主要事实
tell you the main fact about duality
好的
okay
这是真的，我也许会写
this is really and I'll write that maybe
在这旁边，所以做一个二元性如果
here next to it so do a duality if
有一个双重采购LP和双重
there's a dual procure LP and that dual
将做一个最大值而不是一个
is going to do a maximum instead of a
最低和成本是
minimum and the cost is is going to
从原始问题涉及B所以
involve the B from the primal problem so
这现在称为原始问题
this is now called the primal problem
这是它的双重所以有双胞胎
and this is its dual so there are twin
他们使用相同数据的问题但是
problems they use the same data but
完全不同，就像转置一样
quite differently it's like transposing
事情如此让我们称之为未知的Y.
things so so let's call the unknown Y so
因为y是右手边
for y to be the right hand side over
这里是1M的，这样的最大化
here is M by 1 so that's maximize that
我们受制于什么
we're subject to what are the
约束好成本函数
constraints well the cost function over
这里看到成本向量进入了
here see the cost vector goes into the
约束和我认为更大
constraints and I think the greater
等号因为明显变得少了
equal sign because obably becomes a less
或等于签名a得到调换我
or equal to sign the a gets transposed I
认为这可能是
think that's probably probably the
双重约束，它发生了
constraint in the dual and it happens it
不需要Y我们没有更大的y
doesn't need Y we don't have y greater
在这里等于0确定这是一个双重
equal 0 over here ok so that's a dual
它有一个线性成本的问题
problem it has a linear cost it has
它可以是线性不等式约束
linear inequality constraints it can be
你可以通过单纯形法解决
solved by the simplex method you could
选择你是解决那一个还是
choose whether you solve that one or
这个因为如果你解决了一个你
this one because if you solve one you
解决另一个
solve the other
两者紧密相连，那就是
the two are closely connected and that's
二元性的关键理念也许我会
the key idea of duality so maybe I'll
把想法首先是小麦的
put the idea first of all of wheat
二元性，说这个
duality which says that the this
我们试图最大限度地量
quantity that we're trying to maximize
我们得到它尽可能大的
we're getting it as large as possible is
总是少于等于任何C的
always less lesser equal to any C
转X这是任何这是
transpose X this is for for any this is
任何可行的任何可以任何任何可以
for any feasible allowed any can any any
满足的X＆Y
X&Y that are that satisfy the
约束记住可行的手段
constraints remember feasible means
在其他方面满足约束
satisfies the constraint so in other
言语这个问题这个最大化
words this problem this maximization
你试图推动它的问题
problem you're trying to push this up
你正在尝试的最小化问题
the minimization problem you're trying
把它拉下来很容易显示出来
to pull this down and it's easy to show
B转置它的那个很容易
that the one that B transpose it's easy
表明不平等让我们这样做
to show that inequality let's do that so
B转置Ytrue应该是一行
B transpose Y true should be a one-line
证明所以B转置Yok我该怎么做
proof so B transpose Y ok what do I do
所以B转置Y好我在这里看看
so B transpose Y well I look over here
那就是B出现的那个X.
that's where B shows up that's X
将转置Y转置为右，因为B
transpose a transpose Y right because B
是斧头
is ax
我是可行的所以我的B是X和任何人
I'm feasible so my B is a X and for any
X，这是因为这是任何X是b
X this is for this is for any X that B
会是斧头所以我到目前为止都很好
is going to be ax so am I good so far
现在我该怎么办，但现在我看这里
and now what do I do but now I look here
我看到一个转座Y坐在里面
I see a transpose Y sitting right in
在我面前所以我说得好，除非或
front of me so I say well ok unless or
等于，我想我已经完成了
equal to and I guess I'm done a
转换明智少于或等于C所以我
transpose wise less or equal to C so I
有X转置CC转置X.
have X transpose C C transpose X
如此平等，等于这个更少或
so so equal this equals this less or
等于我的弱二元性是
equal that I've got it weak duality is
只是把要求放在一起
just put together the the requirements
在x和y上，你有它但是说出来
on x and y and you have it but word it
这是重要的，你知道如果
was this important you know if the
数学是对一切都已经
mathematics is right everything has to
请它发挥它的作用等等
have it please play its role and so
什么是X的作用大于等于零
what's the role of X greater equal zero
如果我们只是偶数，为什么我们需要X.
there why do we need X if we just even
想到一个平等的只是数字Y.
think of an equal one just a number Y
我们在哪里使用X的事实
where do we use the fact that X is
大于或等于0我们是否使用它
greater or equal 0 do we do we use it
这看起来如此顺利，因为a
this looks so so smooth because a
转置Y我会记下X
transpose Y I'll write down as X
转移C只是为了这一刻
transpose C for the moment just just so
你的眼睛说同样的X转置和
your eye says the same X transpose and
a转置Y小于C
the a transpose Y is lesser equals C
其中X大于等于零
where is X greater equal zero coming in
是
yes
是的，这是真的，但我想看到
yeah that's true but but I want to see
是的，所以这是我的观点，事实
yeah so here's my point that the fact
转置Y小于C
that a transpose Y is lesser equals C
这非常重要，但如果是X.
that's fine highly important but if X
是消极的，这将是另一种方式
was negative it would be the other way
你会想到另一种方式吗？
you would you would get the other way
你不会得到你想要什么，所以
and you wouldn't have what you want so
我们确实使用了X的事实
we really do use the fact that X is
如果我有，则等于零
greater equals zero to say that I have
国家等于这个然后我成倍增加
national equal this and then I multiply
通过积极的东西，然后我仍然
by something positive and then I still
我们没那么好，所以每一个都是
have less we okay good so every it's the
数学是对的，一切都发挥了作用
math is right everything does its part
然后当然是美丽的
and then the of course the beautiful
结果重要的结果是
result the important result is that
刚刚被称为强烈的二元性
there's strong duality just called
现在最大的二元性
duality which is that at the maximum now
这不是任何x和y，但这是
this is not for any x and y but this is
因为这将是4倍
for this is going to be 4x
为什么明星赢家和X明星
why star the winner and X star the
赢家平等等等，这是我们的
winner equality holds so that's to our
双重问题中的最大值是
the maximum in the dual problem is the
与原始的最小值相同
same as the minimum in the primal
问题二见过没有
problem the two have met there is no
一些非线性的二元差距
duality gap in some cooked up nonlinear
问题可能存在差距
problems there could be a gap between
最大和最小但你希望
the maximum and the minimum but you hope
不是，这里的大定理不是
not and here this the big theorem is not
你把这个推出去是件有问题的
there equal a matter you push this out
推下去，这是另一种方式
push that down so that's another way to
说二元性就是这就是我
say that duality is that this is I'm
我可以把它推到某个地图上
pushing that up at some map I could
将其写为最小值
write that as a maximum of a minimum
如果我等于最小值
equaling a minimum of a maximum if I
想要它是线性的二元性
wanted so it's the duality in linear
编程和一个女人一样
programming was the same as one woman's
极小极大定理及其定理应用
minimax theorem and his theorem applied
对于双人游戏而言，关键是凯夫
to two-person games so the kief the key
数学的结果是，这是偶
math result is that that is duality for
线性编程，它会
linear programming and it's gonna be
你会看到同样的事情发生
you'll see the same thing happening for
双人游戏，这是一个极小的动画
two-person games and it's a minimax
定理或鞍点或它只是
theorem or a saddle point or it's just
事情出来是的，是的，所以只是为了
things come out right yep yep so just to
提到数学编程
mention that mathematical programming of
课程包括更加困难
course includes much more difficult
这是线性编程的问题
problems this is linear programming that
你看到的问题是一个美丽的问题
problem as you see is as a beautiful
简单的理论和关注
simple theory and the paying attention
正在关注算法
is paying attention to the algorithm
因为你有两个重要的选择
because you've got two important choices
他们都得到了高度发达
and they both get highly developed
现在好了，所以对于游戏现在我要转
now okay so for game now I'm gonna turn
我会做一个最大流量的例子
to well I'll do a example of max flow
等于最小切割看什么，然后去
equal min cut to see what and then go to
两个人的比赛，所以这里是一个
two two person game so here's a here's
一个例子
an example
好吧所以我从一个图表开始是的，让我
okay so I start with a graph yeah let me
只是如此，这是这是源
just so this is the source this is the
下沉，我正在通过
sink and I'm sending flow through the
网络所以我是一个网络
network so it's a network that I'm
发送流量，所以我的工作就是这样
sending flow through so I'm so my job is
最大化是的，我将X设置为
to maximize yeah is to I'll set X at the
源是零，然后流
source to be zero and then the flow the
总流量会进入水槽所以我
total flow will come into the sink so I
想要在水槽中最大化X，这样就可以了
want to maximize X at the sink so it's
线性规划及其应用
of linear programming and their
约束那么约束是什么
constraint so what are the constraints
每个Edge都有容量让我们看看
every Edge has a capacity so let's see
假设Edge有容量5让我
suppose that Edge has capacity 5 let me
让我把能力放在所有这些边缘上
let me put capacities on all these edges
2134我只是在这里刺伤
2 1 3 4 I'm just stabbing around here
让我说-好吧我不知道是什么
let me say - ok I have no idea what's
发生在这里
happening here
但如果我们可能会看到问题
but if we see the problem we'll probably
能够解决这些问题
be able to solve it so so these
约束是流量变量
constraints are that the flow variable
这将是为什么
which would be would be the why that
在那里我试图最大化无法
where I'm trying to maximize cannot to
普通的流量
the amount of flow just in ordinary
单词边缘的流量
words the amount of flow on the edges
不能高于容量
can't go go higher than the capacity
我可以沿着这条边发送十一个但是
I could send eleven along this edge but
然后我无处可去
then I've got nowhere to send it after
我可以在发送以及九百
that I could send well nine hundred on
那边缘但显然会得到
that edge but obviously it would get
卡在那里所以问题是什么
stuck there so the question is what's
我可以发送的最大值
the maximum I can send through that
网络这是一个经典的问题和
network it's a classical problem and and
事实上，这是一个整数编程
in fact it's it's an integer programming
问题我这些都是整数
problem I these are all integer
容量我可以坚持整数
capacities I could insist on integer
流动，但它是一个非常显着的整数
flows but it's a very remarkable integer
问题，因为我可以允许分数
problem because I could allow fractions
答案不会是不会
and the answer would not be it would not
涉及换句话说分数，如果我
involve fractions in other words if I
把它作为一个整数的问题，则
keep it as an integer problem then the
数学是用于较硬的绝对
mathematics is definitely harder for an
整数问题有什么不同所以
integer problem what's different so so
x可以是整数，也可以是整数
the x's could be integers or they could
是真正的实数，在这里他们
be real real numbers over here they were
实数我碰巧得到一个整数
real numbers I happen to get an integer
为此，如果我放了，如果我有10
for this but if I put if I had 10
跨越15维的飞机和
crossing planes in 15 dimensions and the
整数将完全丢失，但是
integers would be totally lost but the
点在这里，如果我允许真实
point is here that if I allow real
数字它不会让我更多的流量
numbers it doesn't get me any more flow
获胜流量是整数
that the winning flow is an integer
无论如何，这是一个整数问题
anyway so it's an integer problem which
可以安全放松，你可以安全
can be safely relaxed and you can safely
使用单纯形法或汽车标记法
use simplex method or car markers method
或者在内点法
or in the interior point method
与非整数，因为在
with with non integers because in the
这里的内部你没有结束它
interior here you're not ending it
你可以在整数开始或结束
starting or ending at integers you can
这样做是因为整数答案
do it because the the integer answer
最终会更好还是什么
will be in the end better okay and what
是那个答案
is that answer
我认为我已经具备了这些能力
III think I've made those capacities
像太容易太
like too easy too
哦，我没有这样做，所以应该做什么
oh I didn't do this one so so what shall
我这么说，我就像九岁一样大
I say so I make it large like nine I
不知道什么是最好的
don't know okay what's the best we can
通过该网络做到这一点
do through that through that Network
好吧，我从这里看不到它是什么
okay I can't see it from here yet what
我该怎么办
what should I do
显然在这个简单的问题中我可以
obviously in this simple problem I can
得到任何我想要非常本
get anything I want pretty much to this
到目前为止，但我能做些什么
that far but then what can I do
让我，让我甚至做出19好了，
let me let me even make that 19 okay so
我不是在施加太多限制
I'm I'm not imposing much of a limit on
那边但是这些边缘都是
that edge either but these edges are
非常严格的限制，这些都是
quite tight limits and these are sort of
中间限制你好吗？
intermediate limits well what do you
认为是我能发送的最多
think is the most I could send through
你怎么能告诉我我的意思
and how would you show me that I
无法发送更多关键
couldn't send more that's the key
问题我想得到一个约束
question I want to get a bound on an
这个最大值的上限就是这个上限
upper bound on this maximum this maximum
进入水槽的次数少或相等
getting into the sink is less or equal
到什么什么号码，你会
to and what what number would you
建议我可以通过我获得一千
propose could I get a thousand through I
可以开始，但我当然不会
could start but of course I I wouldn't
在那里平铺我无法进一步
tile up there I couldn't get further
你觉得我最擅长什么？
what do you what do you think the best I
可以做
can do
十，我不能做十多怎么样
ten I can't do more than ten how how
我可以做十二十二十二这个权利
could I do ten twelve twelve this right
所以我看到他这样，才能这样啊
so I I see him that way can this yeah
绝对你可以分裂然后这个
absolutely you can split and then this
这可以到这里，那会是
can this go here and that would would be
能够去那里我可以得到十
able to go there so I can get ten
我能做得更好吗？
correct can I do anything better
哦，我可以用这种方式发送一些东西
oh I could be sending some up this way
同时我可以得到三个
at the same time so I could get three
在顶部
along the top
我可以这样就像拍卖一样好
I could so this is like an auction okay
我们可以得到13分
we can get up to 13 can we get so that
这是三个这样的方式和十个
that was three going this way and ten
走这条路是13，我不能
going this way is 13 and can I not
超过13我听到40是啊我有
exceed 13 do I hear 40 yeah oh I've got
一个很大的空间多了一个
a lot of room for one more
好的，所以14很多孩子，我也好
so okay so 14 many kids alright do I
听到15如果我做了12然后我会做什么
hear 15 if I did 12 then what would I do
我把两个送到这里好吧我要做什么
I send two up here okay what am I gonna
从这里与他们一起发送他们
do with them from here send them up
再一次，然后现在你呢
again and along but then now you then
我现在拥有的三个是什么
the three that that I had right now what
将是一个问题的回归，我
would be back of one problem and I'm
寻找知道什么时候退出的必然
looking for a bound to know when to quit
要知道我什么时候优化了那个
to know when I've optimized that's the
二元性的整体观念是找到一些
whole idea of duality is to find some
我想要推倒的最重要的事情
upper thing that I'm trying to push down
但我不能超越它，所以我
and but I can't go beyond it so so I
不要以为我能得到更多
don't think I could get more than to see
一切都必须穿过这个中间
everything has to cross this middle so
三，四夜我不认为我
three and four night I don't think I
可以
could
B23有人说24比23我
b23 somebody said 24 more than 23 I
会因为我而非常怀疑
would be very doubtful because I
无法穿越中间但是
couldn't get it across the middle but
然后我可以得到23我怀疑它
then can I get 23 I doubt it
也许最好可能14，那怎么会
maybe 14 as best possible so how would
我们表明，14是最好的，我认为
we show that 14 is best possible I think
如果我能找到这个就叫做
if I could find so this is called the
切这个削减在这个网络中，从而
cut a cut in this in this network so
是的，我看到像你那样的剪裁
yeah I see a cut a cut like there you
看到流量的每一点都有
see that every bit of flow has got to
交叉切割和总容量
cross that cut and the total capacity
穿越是3和1和2
crossing is the 3 and the 1 and the 2
和8这是14所以我无法得到
and the 8 which is 14 so I can't get
超过14通过不知何故
more than 14 through and somehow that
切割装载到容量可能那些
cut is loaded to capacity probably those
所有边缘都必须做到完全
edges all all have to be fully up to
那么容量就越过了切口
capacity then that crossed the cut so so
切割是边缘的分离
the cut is is a separation of edges that
选择一个源和对不起的节点
go with a source and sorry nodes that go
与此去一个源节点
with a source nodes that go with this
事情是的，然后它是边缘
thing yeah and and then it's the edges
越过切口所以我是的，没关系
across the cut so I yeah is that okay
对于一个例子，这样的二元性的
for an example so that's the duality the
最大流量竟然是14和
maximum flow turned out to be 14 and the
最小切割结果是14和什么时候
minimum cut turned out to be 14 and when
那些匹配14等于14我知道我
those matched 14 equal 14 I know I'm
通过我知道我通过因为我
through I know I'm through because I'm
能够通过14而我永远不会
able to get 14 through and I could never
得到更多是的3＆4＆6＆8是啊好的
get more yeah 3 & 4 & 6 & 8 yeah okay
当然还有一个大网络
and of course the in a big network
切割是最大的切割不去
the cut is the maximum cut is not going
很好看，你不知道
to be visible well you couldn't you know
他们会有数以千计的优势
they would have thousands of edges you
看不到你在做什么，但是
couldn't see what you were doing but but
你可以快速解决这个问题
you could solve this problem fast
实际上很快，而且这很重要
actually fast and and it's an important
在实践中，这是一个重要的例子
in practice it's an important example a
很多其他东西都适合
lot of other things fit into the
max-flowmin-cut示例，因此
max-flow min-cut example and therefore
解决它比我没有更快哦
solving it in faster than oh I didn't
甚至说速度
even say about speed
所以单纯形法几乎总是如此
so the simplex method almost always its
一般情况书房斯皮尔曼谁在
average case den Spielman who was on the
这里的教职员工非常棒
faculty here who's just terrific in this
该地区可能是最先研究的地区之一
area was maybe among the first to study
平均情况也是如此
the average case so so for a for an
取而代之的是a和B和C的平均选择
average choice of a and B and C instead
做出最糟糕的选择
of making the worst choice for the worst
选择你可以创建一个可行的集合
choice you can create a feasible set
它必须去角落角落
that it has to go corner Corner corner
角落直到结束所以
corner until to get to the end so the
单纯形法将呈指数级增长
simplex method would take exponentially
但是这种情况非常罕见
long but that's extremely rare doesn't
在实践中发生我认为和
happen in practice I think and the
平均值是多项式，所以它很快
average one is polynomial so it's a fast
方法平均这个，但我们可以
method on average this but and we can
显然这是一个着名的结果
show actually that was a famous result
它来自俄罗斯那个线性的
it came from Russia that that linear
编程是在P和LP之间进行的
programming is in the big P versus LP
世界线性规划与P一致
world linear programming goes with P
线性规划是一个可以解决的问题
linear programming is a problem that can
在多项式时间内求解单纯形
be solved in polynomial time the simplex
方法不会总是这样，但它可以
method won't always do it but it can be
做了耶和华来到这个世界
done yeah there came into the world
椭球方法，有一个
ellipsoid methods and there was a
激动人心的时间来决定线性
exciting time to decide that linear
编程实际上是P而不是LP
programming was actually P and not LP
是的好，所以这是一个案例
yep okay so that's okay this is a case
您可以理解的二元性
of duality where you can understand
你可以通过国家购买这种二元性
duality you can buy this by the state
流量不能超过容量
that the flow can't exceed the capacity
削减，所以这是什么二元性
of the cut so that's what duality is any
它必须要少于Rico的容量
flow it has to be less Rico the capacity
任何削减他们的能力是总和
of any cut their capacity being the sum
在一个如此当然也有其他
of the one so of course there are other
那截切，必须传中，但是
cuts that cut has to be crossed but
这是三七十二十二
that's got three seven fourteen twenty
两个容量，所以它的十四个容量
two capacity so it the fourteen capacity
这是最小的，我给了
was the was the minimum and I gave the
最大不错是不是很好
maximum nice isn't that nice
是啊好了，还有另外一个世界在这里
yeah okay so there's another world here
也有两人游戏
of two person games that also has
二元性，可以表达，所以让我
duality and could be expressed so let me
今天终于谈谈了两个人
just talk finally today about two-person
所以这两个人都是X＆Y
game so the two persons are X&Y of
当然还有其他很好的名字
course what other names good they have
并且有一个矩阵参与其中
and there's a there's a matrix involved
这是支付矩阵，所以让我来看看
this is the payoff matrix so let me take
一个非常简单的游戏，所以X正在进行
a very simple game first so X is going
选择其中一行，Y是
to choose one of these rows and Y is
要选择其中一列和
going to choose one of these columns and
让我们说从x到y的收益我喜欢它
let's say payoff from x to y I like it
这种方式因为这样X，其疼痛是
that way because then X whose pain is is
随着X在这里，最小化
going to be minimizing as X was up here
和谁收集的将是
and y who's collecting is going to be
最大化，如在双重所以所以
maximizing as in the dual so so the
好的让我看看我想也许就是一个
payoff well let's see I think maybe one
四到八个可能是一个
four to eight would be a probably a
相当容易的游戏玩，这样所以很
fairly easy game to play so that so it's
两人游戏零和游戏
a two-person game zero-sum games
一些意味着所有人都付出了什么
some means that means all all pay what
前付款是为什么为什么得到所有前任
ex pays goes to why why gets all that ex
这里没有第三方没有
pace there's no third party here no
涉及的律师还好，所以会和
lawyers involved okay so what would and
为什么要选择一个列而X是
why is going to choose a column and X is
要选择一个X想要的行
going to choose a row an X wants to make
它很小，Y想要大做好
it small and Y wants to make it big okay
那么这场比赛会发生什么
so what happens in this game
你选择做什么让它变大呢？
what does y choose to make it big the
第二列X选择做什么
second column what does X choose to make
它排在第一排，所以它会是
it small the first row so it's gonna be
如果Y保持，那么也要关注它
focus in on that too because if Y keeps
选择第二列是最好的
choosing that column two is the best the
至少是X将不得不支付
least that X is going to have to pay to
他通过选择而实现了这一目标
and he achieves that by choosing the
第一排所以这是一个简单的游戏
first row so it's a simple game that's a
鞍点它是y的最小值
saddle point it's a it's a minimum for y
在它的列中，它是X的最大值
in its column and it's a maximum for X
在它的行，但当然是矩阵和
in its row but of course a matrix and
其他矩阵可能没有这样的
other matrix might not have such a
马鞍点，所以你可以看到没关系
saddle point so that may do you see okay
本场比赛，这将是一个排序的
with this game that would be a sort of
直截了当的游戏简单
straightforward game where simple
策略第二列每次第一行
strategy column two every time row one
每一次都是最佳的，但现在让我
every time is the optimal but now let me
只是交换那个
just exchange that
所以再次x1和x2y1和y2或他们的
so again x1 and x2 y1 and y2 or their
两列现在发生了什么
two column what happens now
以及为什么有点喜欢大数字
well why kind of likes the big number
八，那么第二个
eight there so goes for the second
第二列仍然有更大的
second column still has the bigger
因此Y的目标是第二列
numbers so Y aims for column two
但那么X做什么行做x
but then what does X do what row does x
选择y是否在列中
choose if y is in there column to the
第二个没关系，所以我找到了一个马鞍
second okay so so have I found a saddle
Y选择此列X的点
point where Y chooses this column X
选择这一行是一个马鞍点
chooses this row is that a saddle point
不，因为现在他会做什么，他看到了X.
no because what will Y do now he sees X
一直选择第二行并且
choosing the second row all the time and
为什么看到了在四非常诱人
why sees a four very tempting for in
该行桑尼是要选择y一个
that row so Y is going to choose y one
第一列通常不是全部
the first column pretty often not all
时间，因为如果他只是发生了什么
the time because what happens if he just
如果Y选择该列的所有时间
if Y chooses this column all the time
那么X会选择这一行而只有
then X will choose this row and only the
收益只会是一个事情
payoff will only be one so that things
为什么他们如此如此，他们走下坡路
went downhill for why they're so so this
不是一个鞍点，我们做什么
is not a saddle point and what do we do
混合策略这就是我们选择的原因
mixed strategy which is why we'll choose
两列有一些概率
the two columns with some probabilities
添加到一个
that add to one
所以BIA所以有第三个
so so the BIA so there be a third
px1和one抱歉的可能性
possibility that px 1 and one I'm sorry
py1P乘以此列，1减去P.
py 1 P times this column and 1 minus P
乘以第二列，这样就是P.
times the second column so that'll be P
加1减去P乘以8和4p加
plus 1 minus P times 8 and 4p plus
一减去P乘以两次就是这个
one minus P times two that's that's this
通过混合他的策略混合列
mixed column by by mixing his strategy
为什么我们有一个像第三个战略
why we have a strategy like a third
人为什么三，当然是X
person why three and of course the X is
一段时间后会注意到什么
going to notice after a while what what
这是一个开放的策略
what the strategy is this is an open
竞争你，你没有隐藏
competition you you're not hiding
他们无法掩饰你的任何东西
they're not able to hide anything you
可能会很好，也许Y会跳来跳去
might take well maybe Y will jump around
但那是愚蠢的Y即将结束
but that's foolishness Y is going to end
找到P之间的最佳选择
up finding the best choice of P between
0和1
0 & 1
它实际上在0和1之间
and it will actually be between 0 & 1
因为列的极端策略
because the extreme strategies of column
1和第2列没有或没有获胜者
1 and column 2 didn't or not winners but
现在X将要做同样的事情PX
now X is going to do the same thing P X
1他要去，他或她将要
1 he's gonna he or she is going to
将这些行组合起来，这样就可以了
combine those rows so so this would be P
1为第一排，1对不起P哦我
1 for the first row and 1 sorry P oh I
更好地选择另一个数字是什么呃
better choose another number what's uh
什么是另一封信而不是PQ好的Q.
what's another letter than P Q okay Q
好的
okay
所以这个角色是一个组合
so so this role was a combination of
那些行所以它是Q加一减去Q.
those rows so it's Q plus one minus Q
次4在第一位置和
times four in the first position and
8加P倍8和1减P
eight plus P times 8 and 1 minus the P
和Q乘以82乘8和1减去Q.
and Q times 8 2 times 8 and 1 minus Q
次2
times 2
对不起，我也写过这个
I'm sorry that I've written this too
小但但会发生什么
small but but what's going to happen
什么将决定P和Q和
what's going to determine P and Q and
如果这些是平等的，那就很好地解决游戏
solve the game well if these are equal
然后会发生什么然后X没关系
then what happens then X is okay with
要么一个人没有X就没有了
either one doesn't X has nothing to
选择是否相等而Y是
choose if those are equal and and Y is
坚持这种混合策略
staying with this mixed strategy which
给了他第三个组合专栏
gives him this third combination column
那么X很好，现在你可能会说得好
then X is good now you might say well
然后X会做它想要的但是X.
then X would do what it wanted but X
如果X没有，它就无法做到它想要的东西
couldn't do what it wanted if X doesn't
坚持X的最佳策略Q.
stick with the optimal strategy Q for X
然后你会利用你的优势
then Y will take advantage so that you
真的，这场比赛已经结束了
really the game settles down to once so
所以这应该是平等的，所以当了
so these should be equal so when the
当那些是平等的，我得到什么IP
when those are equal what do I get IP it
看起来我有8减7p
looks like I have 8 minus minus 7p there
对于第一个，在这里我有对于P
for the first one and here I have for P
减2P是2P加1我得到了
minus 2 P is 2 P plus 1 did I get that
可能是的
possibly right
-对于P-2P是达到峰值并始终
- for P - 2 P is the to peak and always
-是啊好了，这些都是平等的，
- yeah okay so those are equal and that
告诉我9p是6而P是2/3所以
tells me that 9p is 6 and P is 2/3 so
原来那是最好的策略
that turned out that the best strategy
因为y是第一列的2/3
for y is 2/3 on the first column which
看起来不那么有希望和1/3
didn't look so promising and 1/3 on the
第二，通过创造它
second and by that by creating that
策略这些数字是什么来的
strategy what what do these numbers come
出去，他们应该来
out to be and they're supposed to come
对于PPlus来说是相同的，所以4次2/3
out equal so for P Plus so 4 times 2/3
是8/3加1减去P是1/3x加2/3
is 8/3 plus 1 minus P is 1/3 x plus 2/3
是十分之三，所以我认为这是十
is 10 thirds so I think that this is ten
三分之一，如果不是三分之一
thirds and if that one isn't ten thirds
我很惊讶所以它是2/3
I'm very surprised so it's 2/3
对P-P来说是好的，是的告诉我
well is it for P - P yeah tell me
我把它们设置得相同，它们是一样的
they're the same did I set them equal
是的，我把它们等于找到和平
yeah I set them equal to find peace so
他们必须是相同的，除了
they have to be the same except for
教练的错误，从来没有发生过
instructor mistakes which never happened
好的，那些应该是平等的
ok so those are those should be equal
然后X别无选择哦无路可做
then X has no choice oh no way to do
最好选择他的这些专栏
better choose these columns that he
不能选择那些列免费的那些
can't choose those columns free those
因为Y可以自由行驶
roads freely because Y could take
除非如此，否则这将说明这一点
advantage unless so this would tell this
将为q4提供最佳策略
would give the best strategy for q4 for
对不起，对于X是最好的q4
the sorry the best q4 for X yep
是的，你现在看到那张照片吗？
yes do you see that picture now there
可能是其他可能更大
could be other it could be a much bigger
矩阵当然可能还有其他
matrix of course there could be other
列假设有一个00列
columns suppose there was a 0 0 column
会产生什么影响
what difference what would be the effect
关于如何实现的最优策略
on the optimal strategy of how
附加列，附加选项
additional column that additional option
为Y3好，他不会好走这样
for y3 well he wouldn't take okay so
让我们更加诱人101010
let's make it more tempting 10 10 10
好的
okay
哦，他不会告诉你，是的，是的
oh he wouldn't tell you that right yeah
那不太好我不知道是什么
that was not so well I'm not sure what
我想在这里说是的
I'm trying to say here yeah
肯定有可能
there certainly could be there could be
该行是X的列或行说
rows that are columns or rows for X that
不要进入混合状态以获得最佳效果
don't enter the mixed up for the optimal
混合策略并制定一些策略
mix strategy and make strategy of some
一些策略的组合
combination of strategies some
结合纯粹的策略
combination of pure strategies like
选择此列选择该行，但
choose this column choose this row but
某些列可能没有或行可能
some some columns may not or rows may
没有出现在最好的混合物中，所以我会
not show up in the best mixture so I'll
我不会完成这一部分让喜欢
I won't complete that partial so like
那没关系，那么我们怎么看你呢
that okay so what do we do you see that
我们首先得到一个二元定理
we have a duality theorem we first of
所有你能把它写成线性的
all you could write that as a linear
程序未知是P你知道的X.
program the unknown is P for X you know
对于y来说，未知的是X对于X实际上是如此
for y the unknown is Q for X so actually
只有一个未知的简单
just have one unknown in this simple
问题，但对于这个小问题，但
problem but for this small problem but
你有一个最小化和最大化
you have a minimization and maximization
他们在最佳和双重性上相遇
they meet at the optimum and the duality
定理成为for的定理
theorem becomes the the theorem for for
两人游戏线性编程
two person games linear programming
匹配两人游戏的关键点
matches two person games the point about
两个人非常重要三个
two persons is very important three
人类游戏非常复杂
person games are incredibly complicated
不，这个简单的水平会没有sería
no no sería that this simple level would
会解决三人游戏的问题
would solve three person games so that's
其中，约翰·纳什的诺贝尔奖进入
where John Nash's Nobel Prize comes into
图片
the picture
所以他的诺贝尔奖是在经济学方面
so his Nobel Prize was in economics
因为他的应用范围很广
because of the wide applications but he
能够分析和的问题
was able to analyze the problem of and
对于四个以上矩阵的函数
for functions more than four matrices of
三个人或面对面的游戏让你
three person or in person games so you
知道约翰纳什这本书的故事
know the story of John Nash the the book
一个美丽的心灵和电影A.
A Beautiful Mind and the movie A
美丽心灵所以这是其中的一个
Beautiful Mind so it's one of those
涉及麻省理工学院的电影，因为他是
movies that involves MIT because he was
在这里但你无法识别任何东西
here but you can't recognize anything
关于MIT这部电影就像GoodWill
about MIT the movie it's like Good Will
狩猎你，你可能在某些人
Hunting you're you're maybe in some
一些偏远建筑的地下室但是
basement of some remote building but
无论如何，这当然是悲剧性的悲剧
anyway it was of course a tragic tragic
然后肯定和精彩然后
and then sure and wonderful and then
因为他在我这么做的时候再次悲惨
tragic again for its he had so when I
见到他，他会教线性
met him he was going to teach linear
代数一节，但我从来没有
algebra one section but I never
在他成为他的时候发展了他
developed his that was when he was his
精神状态正在走下坡路，他
mental state was going downhill and he
搬到普林斯顿，然后就住了
moved to Princeton and and just stayed
然后奇妙的是他
and then the wonderful thing was that he
改善，然后非常悲伤的事情
improved and then the very sad thing was
它在途中发生车祸死亡
its death in a car accident on the way
家从诺贝尔奖
home from from the Nobel Prize
关于一个惊人故事的故事
so quite a story on an amazing story
是的，所以这是特定的优化
yep okay so that's specific optimization
问题线性规划和
problems linear programming and
双人游戏，我希望周五
two-person games and I hope that Friday
这将是教授大片反正
it will be professor swath anyway the
lecture will certainly be about
讲座肯定会有关
随机梯度下降非常感谢
stochastic gradient descent good thanks